

Ivan Gorkov

Sales Manager

Q 1512 4A, Skopje, 1000, Macedonia, Republic of ivangorkov@yahoo.com +38970373809

Profile

A professional, positive, committed and eloquent Team Leader with excellent communication skills and over 6 years of sales experience in various industries internationally. Now looking forward to being a part of an ambitious and exciting company that offers a promising opportunity for progress and professional challenge.

Employment History

Nov 2020 — Present

Team Leader at TBM Group

Skopje

- Supervising two teams of 5 employees
- Overlooking the running of 2 projects at the same time.
- Recruitment, selection and training of Sales staff members
- Responsible for acquisition and account management for key accounts

Jan 2019 — Sep 2020

Skopje

Senior Sales Representative at TBM Group

- Managing the sales process for new prospects, from initial contact through to closure
- Achieving all revenue targets & objectives while also achieving growth and hitting sales targets by successfully managing the team.
- Working closely with the marketing team to produce any sales collateral required for the target market
- Developing & maintaining successful business relationships with all prospects•Delivering convincing arguments to an executive audience
- Implementing a strategic sales plan that expands company's customer base
- Using Microsoft Office packages, to produce clear and concise reports
- Worked on over 20 successful campaigns in Amsterdam, Brussels, Frankfurt, Berlin, London, USA etc
- Specializing in business events in IT, medical devices, pharmaceuticals, automotive, banking industry
- B2B sales calls with C-level and VP-Level executives
- Contacting IT and Software companies to sponsor the events

Sep 2018 — Dec 2018

Junior Sales Represntative at TBM Group

Skopje

• Exceeded quota by 12%.

Details

Date of birth

30.06.1988

Links

Linkedin

Skills

Business Development Strategies

Innovative Problem Solving

Leadership Skills

Communication

Adaptability

Ability to Work Under Pressure

Project Management Skills

Industry Knowledge

Hobbies

A Bass guitar player who enjoys road trips, playing chess and other strategy-based video games,

Languages

English

Macedonian

German

• • • • • • • • •

• • • • • • •

Jan 2018 — Aug 2018

Skopje

Account Manager and Sales Representative at EXAI

 Main responsibilities were finding and contacting new clients, maintaining the relationship with previous clients, advising them on the current state on their website and possible changes and improvements in order to get a better Google score

Aug 2016 — Dec 2017

Skopje

Account Manager and Sales Representative at BCM Media - Seavus

- Sales of online lottery to new and existing clients over the phone.
- Identifying and registration of potential clients, first sale, up-sale and client contact.

Jan 2016 — Jul 2016

Call Centre Agent at Res-Tel Istrazuvanje

 Performing presentations to potential clients over the phone onvarious financial and marketing subjects

Jan 2014 — Dec 2015

Skopje

Sales And Marketing Associate at DB Survey International

 Cold calling, creating a high number of quality leads with precision, efficiency and consistency

Feb 2012 — Dec 2013

Bitola

Professional English Translator at Freelance

Freelance translation of various documents, contracts and website content.

Education

Oct 2006 — May 2011

FON University - Faculty of Applied Foreign Languages

Bachelor's degree in Professional English Translation and International Business